London, February 13th, 2008
It's Bilal.
I'm in France at last, in Calais.
Is Mina there?
No, she's in class.
Until when?
When is Mina through?
- About 5:00.
- At 5:00.
Hello, son.
Mirko?
I can't talk.
My dad's here.
I'll call her later.
Not here.
Call my cell phone.
No, she doesn't have one.
00...
44...
78...
10...
506...
- Mm-hmm.
- 759.
Okay, tell your sister
I'm in Calais.
I'll get a boat tonight
or tomorrow.
I'll be in London tomorrow.
Okay, but don't
call here again!
Just tell her that.
Okay. Bye.
- Did you buy bread?
- I forgot.
Who was that?
Just a friend.
Excuse me!
Where's the harbor
entrance?
Afghanistan.
Don't understand.
Did the queen
invite you?
Go first class,
it's better!
Not too cold?
Cool it!
Go to the back
of the line!
You stay in line!
Please!
- Where are you going?
- Zoran?
- Go to the back!
- I don't care!
- He's from Mosul.
- Tough!
He's a friend, Koban!
- What are you doing here?
- And you?
Your mom said
you were in London
and doing fine.
I didn't want
to worry her.
How long have you been here?
Huh?
10 weeks.
Me, three months.
- Have you money for a handler?
- I hold on under the trucks.
I don't need a handler.
Here the dogs will get you.
You need a handler here.
- How much?
- 500.
Euros?
- Just to ride in a truck?
- Yes.
I'm skint. Lend me the money.
I'll pay you back in London.
What about trains?
The tunnel?
I can hang on under the train.
I did in Albania!
Trains here do 160.
Everyone who tried it
got crushed.
Hello.
- How are you?
- Thanks.
- And boats?
- What boats?
Fishing boats,
sailing boats...
can't we steal one?
Too many cops, all the boats
are padlocked.
The handlers are
the only option.
I'm 50 euros short.
I'll pay you back in London too.
Well?
Lend me the money?
We go tomorrow?
I'll see.
I'll pay you back, honest.
Is there a phone anywhere?
Aran.
Aran!
- Where to?
- England!
One minute: 10 euros.
The Pizzzza Hut are
looking for bikers.
You don't know London
well enough.
Sure I do.
How would you go
to Osborne Road?
I'd look at the map.
You need the map
in your head.
I'd manage. Better than
washing dishes.
Eat up your meat.
Who's speaking?
Mirko... Bilal.
Can't we eat in peace?
I told you not to call here!
No answer on your cell phone.
Is Mina there?
She can't talk to you.
My dad's here.
Would you like some?
You too?
Who's Bilal?
A friend.
Who is he?
- Huh?
- The Kayanis's son.
What does he want?
Breathe through the hole
because of the CO.
When I say so,
stop breathing and hide.
Put this
over your head.
Shut up!
I'm staying here.
I'll sleep.
Quick!
Hurry!
Hurry up.
Go on!
Move!
You all right?
I've hurt myself.
Put the bag over your head!
Put it on!
Hurry up!
Get down, quick!
Come down!
Quick!
Put it on.
Hurry up!
You'll fuck us all up!
Put it on!
Tighter!
Pilsen, Czzechoslovakia.
What's up?
Put it on, damn you!
People in here!
Hey!
People here!
This'll cost you!
Open the door.
Where's your buddy?
Shit!
Fucking bastard!
Koban, stop it!
Everybody out!
Move it! Get out!
Eyazz? Eyazz!
Eyazz?
Eyazz!
It's all
your fault, asshole!
Eyazz!
Psst!
You owe me 500 euros.
Quiet!
Back off.
I'll kill him.
"Kayani...
Bilal, lraq.
December 8th, '91."
812.
Who's this?
Girlfriend?
Answer.
Your girlfriend?
- Tasty!
- 625 euros 40 cents--
a newcomer!
Cut it out!
- Let go. Let go!
- Stop it, Francis.
- There you go.
- That's enough. Next.
Put that away.
- Let's go.
- Beat it.
Next case:
"Kayani, Bilal:
born December 8th, '91,
Mosul, lraq;
entered the territory
illegally,
arrested 1 5th February
trying to enter the U.K."
Do you acknowledge
the charges?
As a person from
a war-torn country,
you will not be returned
to your border.
But you must know
that strict measures
have been taken
to send people like you home.
Have I made myself clear?
As you have no past record,
I won't place you in detention,
but I don't want
to see you again.
Whatever you heard,
you cannot go to England.
That's over.
Go home,
or you'll be in big trouble.
May I point out
that this boy is under 18?
He's eligible for
a place in a hostel.
He has no desire
to go to a hostel.
Let's not waste time.
Next case.
Next case:
Bafaoua, Malouman...
Calais is there, yes.
Go on, stretch your legs.
There!
That's the way.
Like a frog.
Don't hold the rope!
Let go of the rope!
Come on, bring your legs
together.
Bend and stretch
and together.
Bend and stretch,
then squeezze together.
There!
One more length.
Easy does it.
Yes?
What?
No, not now.
It's cool?
You still owe me
500 euros.
- Let me go!
- Like shit I will!
Piss off!
I want it tomorrow
or I'll destroy you!
When I left lraq...
the Turkish Army
caught me.
They tied my hands and put
a black bag over my head.
And they left the bag
on me for eight days.
You've washed?
Huh?
Soap!
Where did you wash?
Huh?
Please!
All of us have money.
- No, impossible.
- What's going on?
I need some help.
That's how it is!
Scram or I call the police!
Police, okay?
He has a lesson with me.
He's paid.
Out!
No other option.
If I see them again
no more lessons!
Closing time in 20 minutes.
Please go
to the changing rooms.
No, your head's wrong.
Breathe higher, like this.
We'll work on your feet
tomorrow.
We're closing.
Come on, we're closing.
Simon!
- Sorry, we're together.
- Go ahead.
- Together?
- Put it in.
How are you?
- And you?
- Okay. Holidays soon.
- Hey, leave it!
- No, it's fine.
You got the letter?
From the judge?
I did.
I haven't looked.
The hearing
is on Thursday.
I must pick up my Whitman books.
I need them for class.
No, get out of here!
- Beat it!
- What have they done?
Why ban them?
Just doing my job, lady.
Now go!
- What have they done?
- Drop it. It's pointless.
- Answer me!
- He's obeying orders.
Orders from who?
The management.
It upsets customers.
It doesn't upset us.
Does this man shopping
upset you?
Stop bothering
these people, please.
Get out or I'll
call the police, okay?
Well done!
And you don't say a word!
Keep your head down
and run home.
What do you mean?
We can't get sucked in.
- Here.
- No, it's fine.
Know what barring people
from shops means?
Want me to buy you
a history book?
- So what do you do?
- Get angry...
about those assholes' contempt,
about your indifference--
it's almost worse.
I'll collect my books
after tomorrow.
I'll pack them up.
Is Thursday okay?
For the judge?
Oh yeah.
Fine.
See you after tomorrow?
I'll drop by.
I'd like the little desk too.
Yes, sure.
Where are you going?
I'm eating...
with Alain.
Give him my love.
Here you are.
You understand
what I said?
I know him.
Come on.
Thank you.
You've had a shower!
I said no shower!
Don't you understand?
Huh?
Leave it!
Do you understand?
Don't just stand there.
There, okay?
Is that okay?
Don't say thank you
all the time.
What's going on?
What is this shit?
What are you doing here?
What?
You don't off yourself here!
What are
you doing?
What do you want?
Fuck off.
I've had enough.
Why did I get involved?
Want me to tuck you in?
- No keys?
- You could be with someone.
Is that likely?
- Some coffee?
- I don't have time.
- Here, have mine.
- Thanks.
I'm sorting your books.
Who's that?
- Morning.
I'm helping them out.
- Why are they here?
- They were at the pool...
having a shower.
Want these too?
No. How long
have they been here?
I don't know.
Three or four days.
They were on the street, freezzing.
I couldn't leave them.
Thank you.
He's a nutter.
The tall one--
he wants to swim there.
- Where?
- England.
He wants me to train him.
What about your desk?
I don't know.
I can't take it now.
Why are you doing it?
Oh, you know...
no reason.
Yes?
Yes. Why?
I don't know.
You could have problems.
- With what?
- Your Kurds.
No.
My only problem is you.
- Don't. Bruno's downstairs.
- No bickering.
You'll hurt your back.
Take my keys.
Open the door.
- Hi.
What about the desk?
Saturday morning?
Okay.
See you.
- Goodbye.
What's wrong?
- He's sheltering some Kurds.
- What?
I saw two guys coming out.
He knows it's risky?
- Huh?
- I don't know.
He's out of it!
Us now.
Excuse me.
This came from the squad:
"Seen 7::00, Tuesday Feb 18th,
10 Place d'Armes,
a vehicle, grey Clio,
number 5433RS62."
- Your car?
- Maybe. I don't know.
It is yours.
"Taking onboard
two individuals,
probably migrants."
You confirm this?
What?
Taking them onboard.
Why?
What have they done?
Aiding illegal immigrants
is an offense.
Where did you go?
You mean giving lifts
is forbidden?
To them, yes.
There are 500 on the coast,
trying to get to the U.K.,
and more each day.
I'm paid to stop this town
becoming an illegal alien camp.
- So I'll ask you again.
- Why me?
I didn't invite them.
Helping them
encourages others.
We have strict orders to stop
locals helping these people.
So once again:
where did you take them?
To the cinema.
What film?
An English film,
for the language.
Knee, elbow...
Lift those knees,
Mrs. Sanzz!
I'm sorry.
- Shall I keep going?
- No.
Hello, ladies.
Abdominals now.
Lie on your backs
and raise your legs high,
hold it and count to 10.
One, two...
three...
Four...
five...
six...
seven...
eight...
nine...
10.
And again. One...
two...
Can you take over?
Come.
Simon, it's me.
I've been thinking.
You can't shelter those Kurds.
It's heavy shit.
The police watch everyone.
They want to nab us,
close the soup kitchen.
They just arrested a voluntary worker
in Dunkirk.
He could get a five-year
jail sentence!
I'd be off your back.
Stop it.
The judges aren't joking.
I don't know what
you wanted to prove.
Sheltering them
is very kind,
but you must stop now.
Hold on...
I can't talk now.
Promise you'll stop.
Yes.
Take care.
You too.
You're blue with cold!
After swimming an hour.
I didn't bring one.
Call her.
Go on, call her!
Mr. Calmat has taken over
the lease by mutual agreement.
There are no children,
therefore no child support
or family program to ascertain.
As for a compensatory sum,
since you both declare
there is no big difference
in your respective incomes,
we can ignore this.
Have you anything to add?
No, Your Honour.
Mrs. Calmat?
- Mr. Calmat?
- No.
Aspirin.
Thanks.
How do you feel?
It was worth it!
I'm sad.
No ring?
I've lost it.
I looked everywhere.
I feel dreadful.
The ring's
meaningless now.
Can you settle up?
Leave it.
I'll be
right back.
So what about
your Kurds?
We had a trial run in the sea.
He's good.
With training
he'll soon be ready.
Then I'll train
another one,
and another one...
It's not
very complicated.
I'll double my output
this summer.
Out of it...
Your change, sir.
Know why he wants
to cross?
To be with his girl.
He's walked 4000km,
now he wants to swim
the Channel.
I couldn't even cross
the road to get you back.
What are you doing?
You slept here?
You don't get it!
Want me fired?
Get out of here.
That's enough! Beat it!
- You're here?
- He's leaving.
He slept here?
Fucking nerve!
Want a coffee too?
Okay, cool it.
The glide...
30 books, yes...
I stand by
everything I say...
Marion's left.
What happened?
Where is everyone?
The cops came
with tear gas.
They arrested
some guys and left,
just to stop them eating.
- Give me a hand?
- Sure.
Where are they now?
Scattered in the jungle.
- Help me with the other?
- Yes.
He owns two restaurants:
this one and another
near Heathrow.
He's opening a third
in Brick Lane.
He wants me to run it.
Not bad, huh?
You can work with me.
Great, huh?
But on the floor.
Sure. No more
washing dishes!
- Where's Brick Lane?
- The East End.
A busy, trendy street.
Hasan is a fine man.
Isn't he?
- Can I work there too?
- We'll see.
- Can I work on the floor?
- Sure, on the floor!
- Greetings.
- Hello.
- How are you?
- Good.
Hasan--
your cousin.
Remember him?
No problem.
Make yourselves at home.
Good evening.
Welcome.
Come and sit down.
We must be six
for the handler.
I'm looking for guys.
But everyone is broke.
Do you have money?
I thought
you were skint.
I managed.
But you can't come.
No one wants you
in the trucks.
There you are!
You little shit!
- Back off!
- Where's my 500 euros?
Gimme a break.
You're gonna pay me!
Break it up! Shit!
Stop, Koban!
- You'll fucking pay me!
- Knock it off!
What's going on?
Who's Bilal?
Put them to bed, please.
Mina, help your mother.
Now stop calling here.
Mina doesn't want
to see you.
Understand?
She's sick of it.
So stop hassling her!
Leave her alone! Get it?
Who was that?
Who were you talking to?
- Who was it?
- Mina?
Come here.
Come.
I said come here!
Come in.
Sit down.
Sit down!
Thank you.
Hey, you speak French!
Where's my medal?
Where the fuck is it?
I don't know.
I give you food and shelter
and you rob me!
Put it on!
And piss off in your truck!
Do it, put it on.
Put it on!
Fuck you!
You wanna go?
Then go!
I said put it on!
Put it on!
Wait!
Come on.
Were you yelling?
At this hour?
All over, I'm sorry.
Those vagrants again!
- I live here.
- It's illegal.
We don't want trouble.
Trouble?
He's just a kid.
They're illegal!
Don't move!
What's going on?
He's bringing
illegal aliens here.
Drop it.
Look at the state
he's in!
They have lice.
They steal.
- I'll call the manager.
- Go ahead.
Call the army if you like.
Don't you understand?
You're up to something
with him.
What did you say?
Repeat that.
Come in.
Forget it.
Go on in.
What?
Excuse me?
Oh, yes.
My father wants
to marry me off.
I'm to marry a cousin!
What?
A cousin who owns a restaurant.
I don't know him.
What am I going to do?
I'm coming.
Calm down.
When are you coming?
I don't know.
I'm coming.
Tell me what to do!
He doesn't want us
to see each other anymore.
Bilal!
I must hang up!
Mina!
Take it.
Don't mess about.
- Mr. Calmat?
- Yes?
We want to ask you
some questions.
Are you alone?
You can't barge
your way in.
Paul.
Please...
Who slept here?
I did.
Is watching TV forbidden?
No.
Sheltering clandestines?
You can see I'm not.
Did that jerk call you?
You wanted
to hit him too?
No. He's a prize idiot.
Right.
We'll get here
earlier next time.
Bilal?
Pablo!
Come!
He wants you to throw it.
Where did he find it?
Over there somewhere.
Is it yours?
You're sure he went?
Yes, absolutely.
About two or three hours ago,
I don't know.
In a blue wetsuit.
Who are you?
Your name?
Simon Calmat.
- And his name?
- Bilal.
Is Bilal his surname?
What is his surname?
Calmat. He's my son.
How old is he?
Seventeen.
I'll wait.
You forgot about me?
The little desk.
Shit, yes.
Didn't you sleep here?
Hello.
As friendly as ever!
I did tell
you to stop.
And all for what?
When he sees it's hopeless,
he'll come back.
It will be too late
by then.
You called the cops?
The Coastguard.
They won't bother
for a clandestine.
I can't go on, Marion.
Simon.
Eating without you,
sleeping without you--
I'm a mess.
Simon...
don't.
Please don't.
Stop it.
Please.
Simon.
Hello?
Yes.
Again? Why?
I don't know. Later.
When I can.
What's that?
His girlfriend's address.
He left without it.
We mustn't
see each other.
I don't want this.
Nice vibes
in your building.
Come in.
I have some good news:
we fished your son out.
A recent adoption?
How is he?
He's spent five hours
in icy water.
A fisherman spotted him.
They had to drag him
onto the boat.
What are you up to
with that boy?
How do you mean?
You trained him
at the pool.
Two lessons.
And you gave him
a wetsuit.
He nicked it
from my place.
So you admit
you sheltered him?
I have your
neighbor's statement.
He doesn't
like you much.
He implies you have
a "special relationship"
with the boy,
if you see what I mean.
You will be held
for questioning...
for aiding
an illegal immigrant
and people smuggling too.
Expensive.
Your wife is
a volunteer worker?
This doesn't involve her.
We separated eight months ago
and divorced two days ago.
Your neighbor
saw you together today.
My orders are to incriminate
those activists.
I'm under pressure.
Now thanks to you,
I can nab one of them.
Whether she's legally
your wife or not...
is irrelevant.
It's recognizzed
collusion.
Okay. I sheltered
and trained him.
I gave him the wetsuit
and he paid me-- 1000 euros.
Satisfied?
And I fucked him.
I fuck guys.
That's why she left me.
So leave her alone now.
She's not involved in this.
You're on bail.
You're forbidden
to leave the district.
You must
report here daily.
You can go now.
Get out.
Stretch your legs.
Like a frog.
Don't run, you guys!
Come on,
stretch your legs.
- Simon.
- I'll take it.
Do another length, okay?
Can you keep an eye on him?
Hello?
You can't stay here
or the cops
will close the soup kitchen.
Please leave.
You mustn't
be seen with him.
Get off my back.
Go! You'll screw it up
for everyone.
Stop! I'll find him
some clothes.
- Here.
- I'll look after him.
Like that?
Yes.
Go on.
Hello.
Wait a minute,
please.
Why?
Just wait.
So you were
the French 400m champion?
Now you know.
Why didn't you compete
in the '84 Olympics?
The trainer
was a cop.
Is that why
you want to see me?
We found this
on a handler.
A Zoran Lokman
paid him with it.
Did he steal it?
I gave it to him.
Did he get through?
Probably.
He did.
I have bad news
for you, Mr. Calmat.
Where is he?
Here.
The Brits
sent him back to us...
in a plastic bag.
They found him 800m
from the shore--
their shore.
No one's ever
crossed like that.
He had this on him.
I suppose you
gave it to him too?
Hello?
It's me, Simon.
The cops just called.
They said you'd vanished.
I had something to do.
- Where are you?
- In London.
They're looking for you.
They'll take you in.
I know,
but you must come back.
You must stop this.
Simon?
Yes.
Will you come back?
Of course I will.
Good.
Know something?
I found your ring.
No?
Where was it?
Under the sofa cushions.
Are you pleased?
Yes.
I'll come back.
I'm coming back.